Guide to the Disability Covid Chronicles Web Collection TAM.857
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III: Fieldnotes, December 2020-October 2025; 120 websites in 120 archived websites.
  - Open Doors NYC
    - Fire Through Dry Grass, August 2025
      The website contains a synopsis, trailer, and biographies of filmmakers.
  - Oshin, Olafimihan, August 2025
    Article in the Hill on protests outside of the White House in 2022 by people who suffer from Long COVID and chronic fatigue syndrome.
  - Osmundson, Joseph, August 2025; Osmundson, Joseph, 1983-
    Tweet about Mpox.
  - Parents for Responsive Equitable Safe Schools, August 2025
    Website containing charts of weekly New York City COVID case rates, children hospitalized from COVID rates, and child death from COVID rates.
  - Partnership for Inclusive Disaster Strategies, August 2025
    - Ending the COVID Emergency is a Disaster for Disabled People, August 2025; Partnership for Inclusive Disaster Strategies
      Press release by the Partnership for Inclusive Disaster Strategies on the lifting of the COVID-19 Public Health Emergency by the Biden Administration.
    - The Partnership for Inclusive Disaster Strategies X Post, August 2025; Partnership for Inclusive Disaster Strategies
      X post that says, "COVID-19, Here to Stay, we failed. Ending the #COVID Emergency is a #Disaster for #Disabled People Decisionmakers declaring that the loss of 400+ of our people per day does not rise to the level of being an emergency."
  - People's CDC, August-September 2025
    The People's CDC is a watchdog and advocacy group of healthcare, science, and public health advocates and professionals working to provide guidance on navigating COVID-19 for local and federal government agencies.
    - "CDC's HICPAC needs public oversight", August 2025; People's CDC
      Blog post by the People's CDC on oversight for the Center for Disease Control's Healthcare Infection Control Practices Advisory Committee (HICPAC).
    - People's CDC, August 2025
      The website features COVID-19 wastewater data; contagious illness updates; press releases; an external review of the CDC; action campaigns; webinars; and other news updates.
    - Tell Medicare/Medicaid: Hospitals should protect us from COVID-19, August 2025; People's CDC
      Guide for submitting a public comment to the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid to include COVID care in Hospital-Acquired Condition (HAC) Reduction Program and/or its Value-Based Purchasing Program.
    - Universal Masks and COVID-19 Admission Screening Should be Standard of Care, August 2025; People's CDC
      Fact Sheet by the People's CDC on universal masks as standard of care in healthcare.
  - Peters, Gabrielle, August 2025
    X feed of Gabrielle Peters, a disabled writer and policy analyst.
  - Piepzna-Samarasinha, Leah Lakshmi, August 2025; Piepzna-Samarasinha, Leah Lakshmi, 1975-
    - "a long winter crip survival guide for pandemic year 4/forever", August 2025; Zavitsanos, Constantina, 1977-
      Guide to pandemic survival for immunocompromised people in the later years of COVID.
    - "Cripping The Resistance: No Revolution Without Us", August 2025
      Article by Leah Lakshmi Piepzna-Samarasinha on disability activism and justice.
    - "How Disabled Mutual Aid Is Different Than Abled Mutual Aid", August 2025
      Article by Leah Lakshmi Piepzna-Samarasinha on disabled mutual aid.
  - Pulrang, Andrew, August 2025
    Article in Forbes by Andrew Pulrang.
  - Raskin, Jamie, August 2025
    Press release by Jamie Raskin.
  - "The Sequential Organ Failure Assessment (SOFA) and revised ventilator triage guidance: since we are still implementing outdated and more inequitable frameworks now, will we learn any lessons longer term?", August 2025; Schmidt, Harald (Professor of medical ethics & health policy); Roberts, Dorothy E., 1956-; Eneanya, Amaka D
    Article by Harald Schmidt, Dorothy E Roberts, and Amaka D Eneanya on ventilator triage.
  - Schuchman Deaf Documentary Center, September 2025
    Panel discussion on New York City Deaf life during the COVID-19 pandemic.
  - Sick in Quarters Collective, August-September 2025
    Sick in Quarters (SiQ) is a remote disabled artist-led collective.
    - COVID-19 Protest Resources, August-September 2025; Sick in Quarters Collective
      Brochure on how to stay safe from COVID-19 during protests, as well as Know Your Rights information.
    - Sick in Quarters Linktree, August 2025
      The Linktree contains links to events, fundraising campaigns, and the mask distribution network database.
  - The Sick Times, August 2025
    The Sick Times is a news website focusing on the continuing impact of COVID and Long COVID.
    - "Covid-19 in the hierarchy of the Gaza health crises", August 2025
    - "Kennedy's HHS commits to Long COVID, but without clear funding", August 2025
    - The Sick Times, August 2025
  - Sjunneson, Elsa, August 2025; Sjunneson, Elsa R.
    Article by Elsa R. Sjunneson on assisted suicide, quality of life, and triage during COVID.
  - Sommerstein, Michele, August 2025
    Essay by Michele Sommerstein on being disabled in New York City during the COVID-19 pandemic.
  - Soyer, Hannah, August 2025
    Article by Hannah Soyer on ableism at the beginning of the COVID pandemic.
  - Special Support Services, LLC, August 2025
    Special Support Services provides "affordable advocacy, systems navigation, and peer support for NYC families of students with disabilities."
    - "Spread Thin: Survey Reveals Students Without Special Education Instruction", August 2025
      Report by parents and advocates of Special Support Services, LLC.
    - Special Support Services, LLC, August 2025
      Website includes testimonials, community surveys, and an intake form.
  - The Squeaky Wheel, August 2025
    Satirical article on the end of the COVID-19 pandemic.
  - Stolberg, Sheryl Gay, August 2025; Stolberg, Sheryl Gay, 1961-
    Article in the New York Times on the backlash to President Biden's statement on the COVID-19 pandemic being "over."
  - Stratman, Josephine, August 2025
    Daily News article on mask mandates in hospitals in New York.
  - Tran, Lucky, August 2025
    X post by Dr. Lucky Tran on masking.
  - White-Johnson, Jen, August 2025
    Live mural painting event by Jen White-Johnson to honor Black disabled people. Also includes mock-ups for potential other murals by White-Johnson.
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, August 2025
    2 Lizards is a film by Meriem Bennani and Orian Barki that depicted "a surrealist view of the early months of the COVID-19 pandemic as it unfolded in New York City." The film was presented at the Whitney Museum of American Art in 2022-2023.
  - Wong, Alice, August 2021-August 2025
    Biographical Note
    Alice Wong (1974-) is a disability rights activist and founder of the Disability Visibility Project (DVP). DVP was established in 2014 and features articles on "disability media and culture."
    - #HighRiskCA: COVID-19 prioritization for high-risk Californians, August 2025
      Curated list of tweets and articles on the elimination of the "1C phase of prioritized groups for vaccination" in California.
    - "#N95s4UCSF: Call to Action", August 2025
      Blog post by Alice Wong calling for an N95 mask mandate at University California San Francisco Health.
    - Alice Wong Instagram Post, August 2025
      Instagram post about Alice Wong's visit to the Intensive Care Unit.
    - "And Now Here We Are", August 2025
      Article on disabled people's experiences in the United Kingdom during COVID.
    - Coronavirus and the disability community #HighRiskCOVID19, August 2021-August 2025
      Curated list of tweets and articles related to COVID-19 and the disability community.
    - "Disabled Advocates Demand Better Vaccine Access as They Face Greater Risks of Dying from COVID-19", August 2025
      Interview with Alice Wong on Democracy Now!
    - "Disabled Oracles and the Coronavirus", August 2025
      Article on the medical industry complex.
    - Disability Visibility Project, August 2025
      About page for the Disability Visibility Project.
    - "Food Insecurity & COVID-19: Interview with Héctor M. Ramírez", August 2025
      Article on hunger and food insecurity during COVID.
    - "Freedom for Some Is Not Freedom for All", August 2025
      Article on disability rights.
    - "High-Risk Pandemic Stories: A Syllabus", August 2025
      Blog post on the Disability Visibility Project. Links to interviews, guest essays, and podcast episodes on the Project's website.
    - "I'm disabled and need a ventilator to live. Am I expendable during this pandemic?", August 2025
      Article by Alice Wong in Vox.
    - "'It Just Burns Me Up': Disability Activist Alice Wong Reminds California This Pandemic Is Far From Over", August 2025
      Interview with Alice Wong on KQED.
    - "Message from the Future: Disabled Oracle Society", August 2025
      Talk given by Alice Wong.
    - "Night of Ideas", August 2025
      Talk given by Alice Wong on KQED.
    - Q&A with Andres "Jay" Molina and Alexis Neophytides, August 2025
      Article on the documentary, Fire Through Dry Grass.
    - Q&A with Ingrid Tischer, August 2025
      Interview with Ingrid Tischer on end-of-life care and hospitalization.
    - Q&A with Sabrina Epstein, August 2025
      Article on the COVID-19 vaccine prioritization dashboard.
    - Q&A with Tory Cross, August 2025
      Article on vaccine equity in California.
    - "The Political is Personal", August 2025
      Essay by Alice Wong as part of PEN America's "We Will Emerge" project. The project aimed to reach out to voters ahead of the 2020 Presidential Election.
    - "There Is No One Way", August 2025
      Essay by Alice Wong in SFMoMa's Open Space magazine.
    - "What the Disabled Community offered the world", August 2025
      List of tools members of the disability and chronic illness community offered the world.
    - "Voters With Disabilities Face Barriers in 2020 From COVID-19", August 2025
      Article by Alice Wong in Teen Vogue.
  - World Health Organization, August 2025
    X post by the World Health Organization declaring the COVID-19 health emergency over.
  - Zucker, Howard David, August 2023-August 2025
    - Letter from Howard Zucker, August 2023-August 2025; Zucker, Howard David
      Letter from the commissioner of the New York Department of Health on "regulations regarding the use of codeine and tramadol in children and a rare disorder called Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome" in May 2017.
    - Letter from Howard Zucker, August 2023-August 2025; Zucker, Howard David
      Letter from the commissioner of the New York Department of Health on the state of the COVID-19 pandemic in July 2021.
  - #MyDisabledLifeIsWorthy, September 2025
    Tweets using the hashtag #MyDisabledLifeIsWorthy.